We have a place, a compound.
We have a community.
It's safe here.
How many of you are there?
Are any of them children?
Because the fastest way
to get here is by the river,
and I don't think
you could make it with kids.
Listen to me.
I'm only gonna say this once.
We are going on the trip now.
It's going to be rough.
It's gonna feel like
it's going on for a long time,
so it's gonna be hard to stay alert.
It's gonna be even harder to be quiet,
but you have to do both.
You have to do every single thing I say
or we will not make it.
Understand?
Under no circumstance are you allowed
to take off your blindfold.
If I find that you have, I will hurt you.
Do you understand?
It's cold. We have blankets.
Boy, you have your dog.
Girl, you have your kitty.
This is just a place.
There's nothing more that we need from it.
Do you understand?
And no talking on the river.
You must listen as closely as you can.
If you hear something in the woods,
you tell me.
If you hear something in the water,
But you never, ever
take off your blindfold.
If you look, you will die.
Do you understand?
It's okay.
It's okay. It's okay.
- Kitty.
- It's okay. It's okay.
Let's go.
Okay. Okay.
One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight.
Ah.
Twenty-eight, 29, 30.
Okay, this way. It's fine.
Thirty-one, 32, 33.
Where is it? Where is it?
- Uh... asshole, I was listening to that.
- Yeah, so were the people down the street.
The store was packed.
This thing seems serious.
Wow, you literally have no food.
- What... What thing?
- Are you serious?
- I'm serious.
- Turn on the news, dumb-dumb.
Dumb-dumb.
- What channel, dumb-dumb?
- Any one of them.
Airports and train stations
have shut down.
Streets are crowded with people
escaping cities by car and on foot
as witnesses report
unexplained mass suicides.
First recorded in Romania,
there's now an alarming spread
of incidents into Europe and Siberia.
Estimated death toll
is in the tens of thousands.
...don't yet know what is causing
the mass suicides in Europe and Russia.
The eyewitness reports tell of people
exhibiting psychotic behavior.
Our sources are telling us
this does not appear to be
pathological or viral.
US authorities are advising the public
to remain calm.
There have been
no officially confirmed inst...
Well, it's in Russia, so...
Well, try telling that to the soccer moms
fighting over bottled water.
Speaking of which,
I just got off the phone with Mom.
How come I have to update her
about you all the time?
- Why do you have to talk about me?
- I'm not telling her about my life.
At three o'clock, I'm gonna go check out
an Arabian stud in Sausalito.
See, now that is a sentence
you don't hear every day.
- You wanna come?
- I can't. I've got my OB with Dr. Lapham.
- Lapham, when?
- Oh, my God.
Why does your voice get high
when it gets excited?
- How about I drive you?
- No, I'm fine.
I can go in. We can maybe see the baby.
Or I can cancel the appointment
and we can go and see a horse.
No. Fuck the horse.
Wow. Such venom.
What do you think?
I think I see
a whole bunch of people sitting together,
but they all feel incredibly lonely.
The loneliness is just incidental.
It's really about
people's inability to connect.
Inability to connect to what?
- Can you move?
- Malorie.
- I need you to move.
- We've been through this.
- Mm-hmm.
- That's not how it's gonna be for you.
It's different with a baby.
It's an immediate love affair.
- It's not gonna be that way for me.
- Yes, it will.
- No, ma'am.
- You should be afraid of being alone,
not of this.
And what we need to do is get you...
...out into the real world
with other people,
not stuck in this house all day.
You never leave.
Why should I leave?
I have you to get me groceries.
- You have to move.
- No, not moving.
- Yes, you do.
- Not moving.
- Why?
- Not moving. I love my house!
I know it took you a long time
to find a studio you loved,
and ever since Ryan left,
you've gotten a lot more work done.
But, so fine, so no more roommates.
Ryan was not a roommate.
Uh, it turns out he kind of was.
Anyway, can't raise a kid here.
Where would you even put her?
How do you know it's a she?
Wishful thinking, I guess.
Sorry, it's work.
I'll be there in a second.
Hi.
Yeah, they just had
to push the surgery back an hour.
Yes?
Yeah.
I'll call right back.
What?
You still don't wanna know the gender?
And ruin the surprise, Dr. Lapham? No.
How have you been feeling?
Have you been sleeping any better?
Rough.
I never slept well
before I had this condition.
It's called pregnancy.
It's okay to say it out loud.
Oh, don't you know, Doctor,
if you don't acknowledge a thing,
it simply goes away?
Oh, really? All this time, I had no idea.
- When a horse gets pregnant...
- God, the horse.
You know about horses? When a horse
gets pregnant, it knows right away.
Does it?
It changes the way it eats.
It changes its gait.
It bites all the other horses
who come too close.
It's too bad we're not horses.
It is too bad. Great to be a horse.
Then we would have, like, a mother
who would have actually raised us
and a father
off on some faraway stud farm.
Hold on.
Our father was off on a faraway stud farm.
- That is correct.
Poor us.
We should go feel sorry for ourselves
with lunch and a bottle of wine.
Oh, finally,
now you're making some sense.
- Good.
- Really, in front of me?
We didn't mean it...
No, like a tiny glass of rosé
is not gonna hurt the little bean.
I'm pretty sure I heard the word "bottle."
You might want to think of a name
besides "little bean"
seeing as your child
is now the size of a small melon.
Small melon!
I know it's hard to love someone
you haven't met yet.
Oh, that's beautiful.
Thought about stitching that on,
like, a little lavender sachet?
- Could sell them in the gift shop.
- In the gift shop.
You're having a baby, Malorie.
Pretty soon you and I, Jessica,
and some hard-ass labor and delivery nurse
will be on the third floor
making the same wise cracks.
Only this time,
you won't be going home by yourself.
I know. I know.
But if that's not what you want,
there are plenty of couples
who are desperate to adopt a child.
There are no judgments here.
You can make whatever choice you want.
But what you can't do is ignore it
and hope it just goes away.
You okay in there?
I'm great.
Are you puking?
Just go to the car.
Is it chunky?
No, it was actually the really smooth kind
that just shoots out real clean.
I'll meet you at the car, okay?
- In the corridor.
- Let's get it clear.
Hey! Hey! Hey, security!
Watch out. Help. I need help!
No, get back!
- Calm down. Please calm down.
- Code gray. Level one.
Calm down. Security!
- You feel better?
- It's happening now.
You get any on you?
The thing in Russia that's making
everybody crazy, it's here now.
- What?
- Can you just, please...
- Hold on.
- Inside the hospital.
Go, go, go, go!
Go, go, go, go, go!
We're going straight to Santa Rosa.
You can stay at my place
until whatever the fuck this is isn't.
- I don't have any clothes.
- You can wear something of mine.
I'm not much of a chaps-and-boots gal.
You're worried about
what to wear right now?
Well, I find it comforting
to focus on the wrong things.
- Shit.
- What?
There's a car stopped in
the middle of the fucking road.
Stop. Just go round.
Move. Let me go.
If this thing gets any worse,
you'll wanna be off the roads
and on a damn horse, trust me.
- Oh, my God!
- Shit. Shit, shit, shit!
People have to stop being so stupid.
Oh, my God, Jess. Just go. Go.
I'm not running the light
with a pregnant lady in the car.
Just drive the car!
You gotta let me just drive.
You're freaking me out.
- You know what?
- Just let me do it.
- This isn't me.
- My phone is in the back seat.
- It's the foreman wondering where I am.
- Right, just hold your horses.
- Yeah, ha ha.
- What did you do with it?
Oh, my God. What the fuck is that?
What the fuck is what?
What are you looking at?
What did you see? Talk to me.
What the fuck is what?
What are you doing? Oh, my God, Jess.
Jess, don't do that.
Just what are you... What is wrong
with you? No. Stop it! Stop it!
No, no, no!
Stop it! Stop it!
Jess, what the fuck is wrong with you?
Jess, please. Stop it, Jess.
God damn it! Stop it! Please stop it!
- Lydia, what are you doing?
- She's pregnant.
Lydia, not now. Let's go in.
She's pregnant.
You can't help!
Hurry, come inside!
Okay.
Sweetheart, get up. Right now.
Mom.
Please don't go.
Hey. Hey. Hey.
Keep your eyes down.
Open the door.
This woman is pregnant.
- Open the door!
- No.
- Hey! Open the door. Police.
- Don't open it.
- Police! Open the fucking door!
- I'm sorry. It's my house.
Get in. Hurry!
Come on. You good?
Are you okay?
She went to help you.
Now she's gone.
Come on. Now everybody's
obviously just a little freaked out.
- I'm so sorry. I'm so sorry.
- Come in. Come inside the house.
Come on. Come on.
Is everybody all right?
Is anyone getting service in here?
You don't have any Wi-Fi?
I have not gotten any.
Come on.
- It's not working.
- I gotta get a hold of my kids.
No, nothing.
- Honey?
- Nothing. I have nothing.
- They're at home?
- Excuse me.
Mom? Mom, call me. Call me right now.
Something... Hello? Hello?
That thing fucks with your nervous system.
I've seen it in my clients for weeks.
Hey, did I mention I'm a fucking cop?
You're in the Academy.
Doesn't make you a cop.
Whatever it is,
I'm sure they'll send someone soon.
No, the only thing that will happen soon
is we're all gonna die soon.
This has a classic bio-warfare signature.
North Korea or Iran.
Douglas, that's it.
They don't know what it is yet, okay?
We just all gotta try to stay calm.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Please.
We are so fucking fucked.
I think I heard one.
We were running up the street,
and I swear to God, I... I felt something.
- I heard something.
- Did you see it? What was it?
I... I don't know. It was just there.
- The presence?
- Yeah.
So fucking fucked.
Gotta be an image out there.
They must have released some video.
- I haven't seen anything.
- My crew saw one.
- What?
One minute,
we were digging a foundation...
and then my contractor just lies down
in front of the bulldozer.
And then my operator tips the rig
into the ditch and snaps his own neck.
- Oh.
- It seems like if you look at it,
it makes you crazy
or it makes you wanna hurt yourself.
No, it makes you kill yourself.
And you just...
you just look at it.
- And you commit suicide.
- How can that be?
Close the windows. Get the windows!
Close all the windows.
Everybody, get the windows.
Oh, thank you, Jesus.
Andy, Bailey, can you hear me?
Dad? What's that thing outside?
- Bailey! Bailey?
- Bailey.
Bailey! Bailey!
- If you go outside, you'll die.
- My children are out there!
- Move!
- You won't make it to your children!
- It's back on. Turn it up.
- The President has declared
a state of emergency
and has closed all borders.
Do not, do not go outside.
Avoid social media. Use radi...
What? What in the shit is happening?
- It's an end game, man.
- I'm sorry, what?
The end game. Humanity has been judged,
and we've been found wanting.
- Judged? By who?
- They go by different names.
You got world religion and mythology
that's full of mentions of demons
or spirit creatures.
People who've seen these creatures
almost always describe
their encounter as this...
as with an entity that takes on
a form of your worst fears or...
your deepest sadness
or your greatest loss.
Sounds like bullshit to me.
Religious talk.
It's not bullshit, okay?
It's real talk. It's facts.
They come in all different forms.
You got the Aka Manah, the Varios Daevas
from ancient Zoroastrian legend.
You've got the Surgat
from ancient Christian occult beliefs
that made pregnant women encounter
their unborn children as other creatures
such as lobsters or spiders.
You've got the Huli-jing from China.
You've got the Puca from Celtic mythology.
All different names, but the same thing.
And what's that?
The end of us.
Charlie, did you learn all of that
working at the supermarket?
- No, I've been studying it for years.
- In college?
Not college per se, but...
I mean the Internet. That's where you get
all your information from.
- I'm working on a novel, guys.
- Fuck's sake.
So we can't do anything
but wait here until we go crazy like him?
The army is bound
to get this under control.
We just have to wait.
Hey. Hey.
Why don't we sit back down?
No, no, no. I'm fine.
I'm... I'm just trying to make a call.
- Understood.
- I'm okay.
Understood. Understood. Um...
- The phones aren't working right now.
- Okay. Okay.
Listen, are you in any pain?
What? No. No.
- I feel like you may have a concussion.
- I am fine. I'm fine.
- Okay. Okay.
- I am fine.
Okay.
We were just driving.
And then she saw something.
I didn't see what it was,
but then she got this look on her face.
It's like she got...
She got so sad, and Jess does not get sad.
No.
She stepped out of the car
and ran into the street...
and she's not suicidal.
She would never do that.
But it was...
And then that woman...
that woman, she saw me,
and then she started talking
to her mom and I...
That woman was my wife.
- Her name was Lydia.
- Okay.
And she wasn't talking to her mother.
Her mother's been dead ten years.
Hello?
Hello, can anybody hear me? Hello?
Hello? Can anybody hear me? Hello.
Is anybody out there?
Hello, my name is Malorie.
I'm on the river. Is anybody out there?
Hello? Hello? Is anybody out there?
Can anybody hear me? Hello?
Malorie. Malorie.
Malorie.
It's been three days
since these, um, events unfolded.
Station's lines are down.
I can't get in touch with anyone.
We haven't heard anything
from any authorities...
but if you are listening,
from what I can gather,
as long as you stay indoors,
as long as you don't look
at those things...
you should be fine.
Do not go outside.
The moment I receive any more news,
I will be sure to update you.
My husband works in trusts and estates.
What kind of law do you practice?
- Bankruptcy.
- When he's not suing his neighbors.
Hey, how long's
our food gonna last?
Not much longer.
Because some of us
don't understand the concept of rationing.
Douglas, your house is behind this one.
When we finish this,
let's go for a food run.
We'd never make it back.
What you don't understand is...
- Hey, Tom...
- We can't let anyone in.
Okay, just calm down.
- Hello?
- Yes, hello.
- You're making a big mistake.
- Douglas.
- Yes, hello.
- Hello?
My name is Olympia.
I need help. Please.
- Don't open the goddamn...
- I'm gonna open the door.
Fuck!
Okay, one second.
Hey! Hey, hey, hey, hey.
Move.
Go ahead.
Go get a...
Go get a blanket. Go get a blanket.
There should be two lamps
on either side of the door.
I'm gonna hand you a blanket and I want
you to drape it across the both of them.
- Okay.
- Okay?
I need you to block the view for me.
- Cover your eyes.
- So stupid.
Malorie, cover your eyes.
Here. Here. Okay.
Okay.
Let me know when you have it.
Tom, is this safe?
- Shut up.
- Hold on, please!
- Okay, it's all covered.
- Okay.
I got you. Come on.
Hold on. Hold on.
We're good.
- Malorie.
- Yeah.
- The gun, please.
Yeah, before you kill someone with it
since you have no idea how it works.
It's okay.
How...
There are so many of you.
So are you, um...
Are... Are you pregnant?
Yeah. October 1st.
What about you?
Uh, end of, uh, September.
Wait. Hold on. Is shit
still going crazy out there or what?
Are you on your own?
Yeah, I am.
My husband was deployed last month
'cause he's in the Air Force.
I tried to make stuff last
as long as I could, um...
but I was so hungry
and I was afraid I would starve my baby,
so I didn't know what to do.
- Have some water.
- Thank you.
So you left and started knocking
on random doors?
I only live a block away.
Great, now we can all starve
here in the maternity ward.
It just means we need
to get more supplies.
Of course, but we can't get anything
if we can't see.
Oh, we're so fucking trapped.
Maybe not.
Maybe we can see better than we thought.
- What do you mean?
- Come here.
We have cameras around the house
transmitting a live feed.
Come upstairs. Come on.
It's a digitized signal.
It just shows the color temperatures
of the objects. It's neutered information.
- Colors on a flat screen.
- But an image can still have power.
We have no idea
how these things can operate.
These images are not direct.
We can't look at whatever it is
with the naked eye,
but maybe we can with a translator.
Pixels and heat.
Maybe it won't even show up.
Well, we're not gonna find out
until one of us takes a look.
I think it's a huge mistake.
You would, Douglas.
You think everything is a huge mistake.
Sooner or later
we're gonna have to do something.
We don't know how long
we're gonna have electricity.
You gotta trust me on this.
I really think this is gonna work.
Okay. Okay.
Maybe if it does, we could use
the technology for supply runs or...
Exactly.
Just not too tight.
I hope you know what you're doing.
Listen... you and your husband,
you're good people.
You know, it wasn't... It wasn't that.
Thank you, Douglas.
You don't have to do this.
I know. Don't worry.
- Tom, I need the remote.
- Yeah.
There you go, bud.
So why are you suing him?
'Cause they want to tear down
this part of their house
and build some glass monstrosity.
His husband's an architect.
It's his property.
Why do you care what he builds?
Because I have to look at it.
Not a chance.
Well, the world's ending, baby,
so you never know.
Hmm.
Where are you, motherfucker?
Come on, Greg.
Focus.
It's, uh...
It's about the end of the world.
My novel.
But it's not one of those kids' stories
where they all got crossbows
and they're killing each other to survive
or running around some giant maze.
- Mm-hmm.
- No, this story is, um...
This story's gonna be real.
Did you ever think
it was gonna be anything like this?
Greg! Greg, can we come in?
- What's going on?
- Greg!
Greg, can we come in?
Look away!
Cover your eyes!
Cover your eyes. Find the monitor.
- Greg.
- Come on, Greg.
- Greg?
- Shit.
- I've got it here.
Okay! Okay! Okay!
You can open your eyes. You can see.
I fucking told him that it was a mistake.
Come on.
We got to move. We got to move.
- I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
- Come on. We gotta go.
We're never getting out of here.
No one's coming for us.
No one's coming for...
We need to go.
Hi.
Yeah.
I thought it might be good for us
to be close considering...
Sure.
You know,
this way, we won't be lonely.
I read this blog post once
about how pregnant women
should always sleep next to someone
because the baby can sense
when the mother is lonely.
Perfect.
So, um...
have you thought about names yet?
No, not yet.
How about you?
Well, if it's a girl we wanted
to name her, like, Ariel or Jasmine.
I mean, I would love to name her
Cinderella and just call her Ella.
And what did your husband like?
He loves everything I love.
What about you?
Does your husband have a favorite?
Oh, it's just me.
- Oh, I'm... I'm sorry.
- No, it's fine. It's fine.
Well, what about your family?
They must be excited...
Do you know what?
Could you just excuse me for one second?
I'll be right back.
Sorry.
That's something you can't unsee.
Ah, no. No, you cannot.
Yeah.
Sorry.
Shh.
- Shh, shh.
- Hmm.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
I'll wait to do my laundry in the morning.
- That's probably a good idea.
- Yeah, I think so.
Good night.
Hello!
You guys need some help?
- It's okay to take your blindfolds off.
- Do not take your blindfolds off. Do not!
I got some food.
Those kids look hungry.
Get down! Get down! Get down!
Down. Down. Down.
Hey, little buddies.
Have you ever seen a baby deer?
I'll tell you a secret.
I found one in the woods.
Okay. I know you're scared.
Well, listen, there's no need.
I'm not here to hurt you.
I can pull you to shore.
Take your goddamn blindfold off!
Ah!
I've seen one. I've seen the truth.
Take your blindfold off.
It's beautiful. It's beautiful.
Take your blindfold off!
It shall cleanse the world!
Everyone must look.
Got some bad news.
All right. We're running out of food
and there's no help coming.
We've got to get outside.
Look, I might know where we can get more.
- Where, Charlie?
- The Fields market.
I locked the place up
when everything started going crazy.
- You're just telling us this?
- At least we know now. Thank you.
Okay, so we'll need a group of us to go.
Whoa. We'll be dead before we get there.
- Are you kidding me?
- I'll go.
- Well, if he's going, I'm going.
- You're pregnant!
Well, if all you guys are going,
then I can come too.
Why don't I go on the first run
and then you can go on the second run?
- I'll come.
- What?
- It's a death wish.
- I have the training. It'll be fine.
I don't like this.
I don't think anyone should go.
- There are four of us.
- Five. Charlie's going.
Charlie's going?
Charlie ain't going nowhere.
- You know the security system.
- No chance I'm going.
I gave you the information.
That's all you needed.
You don't need me to tell you
where to go. It is a supermarket.
They got signs.
You've been shopping before.
You wanna get cereal,
the sign will say cereals.
If you can't read, I get it,
but you can read.
- No. You don't need me to go with you...
- Charlie. It'll be research for the book.
Okay? Be awesome.
All right, so the idea is if we
can black out all the windows,
it's efficient and it's safe.
Is anybody else hearing this?
How is driving blind safer?
We're not.
We've got the GPS.
Calculating route.
Continue straight.
In half a mile,
turn right onto Bay Street.
- What is that?
- It's a curb.
It's just a curb.
It's a proximity sensor.
Just a speed bump. It's just a speed bump.
Turn right here.
- Are we off the road?
- No, there's something.
- I think it must be just a truck.
- Just go around.
- Keep going around it.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
What was that?
Is somebody else driving out there?
- Charlie, breathe.
- Shit! Fuck this shit.
- Get the fuck out!
- Charlie! Calm down.
Guys, stop touching him.
- Look at me. You have to be quiet.
- Shut him up.
Ah. Ah!
Fuck! We're not gonna make it.
Calm down. Calm down.
- Oh, shit!
- Everybody, hold on.
Hold on to something. Gonna move!
Ah!
Hold on!
That's not a fucking speed bump!
- Fuck, it's stuck.
- Hold on.
- Turn left here.
- Slow down! Slow down!
You have arrived.
What the fuck?
And after all this,
we're supposed to get out now?
Lucky us.
- On three. One...
- I'm ready now.
...two, three.
What was that?
What did I just hit?
That's just a pillar.
Okay. Where's the...
The door should be
just a couple of paces up, man.
- I'm lost.
- Towards your left.
Left. Left. I'm lost.
- Come on, you guys.
- I'm lost.
- Oh, here. Here.
- Okay. Okay.
- You're in?
- No.
Okay. Wait. Almost got it.
Okay, I got it.
Go on.
All right. We're in.
- Hello!
- Shh! Shh!
I'll check the windows.
Here we go. Here we go.
All right, I think we're clear.
You can take 'em off.
Oh, my God.
- Jack-fucking-pot.
- Yeah.
- Where are the canned goods?
- Aisle two.
- Toilet paper?
- Five.
- Fuck that. Where's the booze?
- It's in seven.
Let's not forget. We have limited space.
Stick to non-perishables, the necessities.
- Where are the electronics?
- Go to six.
Six. All right. Cool. Thank you.
I'm not cleaning this shit up.
Sweet.
Boy, I'm glad I tagged along.
This is truly the happiest place on Earth.
I know. You're not kidding!
It's, uh... my baby shower gift to you.
Why, thank you.
Yeah.
So, my sister is
expecting her fourth, so...
Oh, my God. She's a saint.
Yeah, she is.
And I'm always touching her belly.
It's calming.
Yeah, it's nature's dirty little trick.
Is your sister in Sacramento?
- Yeah.
- Yeah?
Yeah.
What about you? Where did you...
Where did you grow up?
Oh, just outside of Stockton.
- Stockton.
- Yeah.
- We raised horses.
- On a real ranch?
- Well, my daddy was a real cowboy.
- That's... That's how you learned your...
- What?
- ...little shotgun trick.
Yeah. I had an interesting childhood.
Hmm.
Ah, but Stockton wasn't
all that far from Sacramento.
No. Just down 99.
- Just down Highway 99.
- Worlds apart, right?
Still we could've met some other way.
Sure.
Could have been your babysitter.
My hot babysitter.
You're... You're only saying that
'cause we're all gonna die.
Possibly.
How did you guys get so lucky?
Huh?
Hi.
Hi, there.
So sleepy.
Attention, all shoppers,
come to aisle seven, please.
I have a big, big, big, big, big
announcement to make.
- Ladies and gentlemen, please...
- Yes, Douglas.
I would like to take this opportunity
to make a toast to all of us...
because all of us, collectively,
are making the end of the world...
great again! Yeah!
Birdies.
I mean, don't you doofuses get it?
Uh, we could just stay here.
We have a year's supply
of food and drink right here.
We don't ever have to pay
and we shouldn't ever leave.
And what are they gonna
do at Greg's? Starve?
Better them than us.
We have everything we need to live here.
Everything.
There is no statistical, logical, or legal
argument for trying to get back there.
Here's an argument: we're not assholes.
And we're not staying.
What is it?
- Somebody let me out of here.
- Charlie, what's behind there?
It's a loading dock.
Hello?
Please let me in.
Speak up, I can't hear you.
Cover your eyes.
- What?
- I'm gonna open the door.
- No.
- There's a person out there.
I have to open the door.
Okay.
Okay. Uh...
- Hello?
- Hello.
Please let me in. I'm trapped.
Wait, wait, wait. Is that...
Fish Fingers, is that you?
- Charlie, yeah, it's me.
- Who's Fish Fingers, Charlie?
He works here at the supermarket with me.
He works in the seafood department.
He's been to prison and he's a bit crazy,
but he's always nice to me.
- How did you get there, man?
- I got... I got...
They tricked me!
Who's they?
Who you talking about?
Are you there alone?
They tricked me
and they left me to rot here.
Who left you to rot?
What are you talking about?
You guys,
there's something wrong.
There's something wrong!
- Please let me in. I'm trapped.
- Hey. Hey. Hey.
What are you doin', Fish Fingers?
What are you doing, man?
Look at it!
It wants you to see it! Let me in!
He's too strong. I can't hold him.
Let me in!
Shit!
Charlie! Charlie! Charlie!
Fuck! Ah!
Charlie, wait!
Look at it, Charlie. It's beautiful.
- Charlie?
- Charlie!
- Oh, shit.
- Oh, fuck.
Fuck!
We gotta go.
We gotta move. Come on. Let's go.
Let's get out of here.
Please. Please let me in.
How is that guy alive in there?
Please let me in.
Hi, Felix!
Oh, my God. Look at all this stuff.
- Birdies?
- Yeah, they, uh...
They seem to sense
when the creatures are around.
Where's Charlie?
Another novel I won't have to read.
He saved us, you fucking asshole.
I know what you think of me,
what everybody thinks of me.
You know, in the divorce petition...
my first wife said that to call me a creep
would be an affront to creeps everywhere.
My second wife said
she no longer feared going to hell,
'cause it couldn't possibly be worse
than being married to me.
Think I would have loved them.
Maybe.
And then Lydia.
Third time really was the charm for me.
She was the kindest person I ever met.
But I'm here and she's gone.
You know why that is?
Because, in the end,
there are only two types of people.
The assholes and the dead.
God, you sound like my father.
Like your father? Why?
Was he a towering intellect given
to dispensing wisdom to undeserving fools?
Yes, he was fluent in asshole as well.
And just like you, he blamed
everything he did on some deeper meaning,
convoluted conspiracy theories and...
how it was everybody else's fault
when he was clearly in the wrong.
But, you know, once my sister and I
realized it was just an excuse
to treat his family like shit,
it made life a little easier.
You know what though?
I see one difference between us.
Hmm?
I'm never wrong.
You are...
You're two pricks in a pod.
Do I look like him as well?
Mm...
Not really.
- He wasn't exquisitely handsome?
- It's not that, it's just...
the hair... the hair is different.
- The hair?
- Yeah.
He had some.
Oh.
Oh, I can't.
Oh, come on, the world is ending.
I really don't think a quarter-ounce
of whiskey's gonna tip the scales, do you?
Well...
I hope you're wrong.
About the assholes and the dead.
I hope there is more.
Here's to hoping there is more.
- Close the garage.
- I've got it.
Wait. Wait. Wait.
- Cover your eyes.
- Yeah.
Okay, okay, okay.
It's closed. It's closed.
Sons of bitches.
Where's the goddamn car?
You guys.
You guys, where are Lucy and Felix?
Fuck.
You stopped rowing.
I'm just taking a break.
How much longer?
A few hours.
Ah!
Malorie!
Malorie! Malorie!
Help!
Malorie!
- Are you okay? Are you okay?
- Yes.
- I'm cold.
- I know. I know you're cold. Hold on.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
All the food and blankets. God damn it!
- I'm sorry.
- No, no, it's...
Hold on.
Okay. All right.
- Okay.
- I'm so cold.
We're gonna get you warmed up, okay?
We're gonna get you warmed up.
Put this around you.
Keep your blindfolds on. Stay tight.
Did you hear that?
Lay down on the bottom of the boat.
Lay down, really flat.
I need you to be quiet.
I'm gonna leave the birds with you.
I'm gonna cover you up, but do not
make a sound and do not leave this boat.
Understand? Do not leave this boat!
Shit.
Malorie.
Something is wrong with Malorie.
Ah! Ah!
Malorie?
I told you to stay on the boat.
You don't think.
You do exactly what I say or you die,
do you understand me?
If something happens to me,
do not try and help me.
Forget about me and try to save yourself.
Do you understand?
Say it! If something happens to me,
what do you do?
You save yourself. Say it!
- I save myself.
- You save yourself.
I can't trust you.
The end of the world makes us do things.
- It's not the end of the world.
- Really?
It sure feels like it.
At the end of my deployment in Iraq,
we were stationed at this village...
ordered to patrol the streets,
make sure everybody was safe.
One morning, we saw...
this father walking with his four kids.
So I pulled over to make sure
everything was okay
and to make sure he got
wherever he was going safely.
Come to find out,
he was walking his kids to school.
In the middle of all that shit,
all that chaos,
he was walking his kids to school.
So...
So we just followed him.
Day after day.
We escorted him.
That just became our routine.
And then, at the end of our time,
he gave me this
when it was time to come back home.
Mm.
I like to think he's still
walking his kids to school.
Hello, can anybody hear me? Hello?
This is Malorie.
Anybody, can you hear me? Hello?
Can anybody hear me? Hello?
Hello? Can anybody hear me?
Hello? Testing, hello?
Hello, is anyone out there? Hello?
Can you hear me, please?
- Hello? Testing.
- Are you a...
Do you have a blindfold on?
You do.
Is... Is the blanket behind you still up?
Ah...
Okay, just come in really, really quickly.
Thank you. Here's my blindfold.
Thank you so much.
It's okay. Just wait. Wait here. Malorie!
- I gotta pee.
- Olympia, what are you doing?
- Malorie!
- What are you doing?
- What are you thinking? Get down!
- Okay, he's just scared.
- He's just scared.
- Tom. Check the bag.
Get over here, Olympia. Get over here.
- Who are you?
- Who is this guy?
Tom, I've got him. Check the bag.
Check the bag.
- Who is this?
- He's just scared.
- Who are you?
- How did he get in here?
- Shut up, Olympia. Who are you?
- He was scared, okay? I just let him in.
- You let a stranger in the house!
- I'm sorry.
- He was terrified!
- Are you a simpleton?
Oh, God. Okay. Please.
My name is Gary.
I live in the city.
When these things came, I got
the first train out with some colleagues
because we thought it would be safe.
Please, please just let me stay here.
They're after me.
Who's after you?
- I don't believe it. He's lying.
- Who's after you?
It's obvious he's lying.
- I swear.
- Why are you here?
We went
to my colleague Carl's house to lay low.
Everything was fine until they broke in.
Creatures don't break into people's homes.
No, not the creatures, these psychos.
These psychos from Northwood.
Northwood?
I don't... Where is that?
It's a mental institution
for the criminally insane.
Well, it's nice to know
they have hall passes now.
And then what?
They took us outside
and they forced our eyes open
so that we would have
to look at the creatures.
What?
- Did you look?
- No.
Somehow, my friend Carl managed to tackle
one of these people to the ground
and the rest of us made a run for it.
I just kept on running
and running and running till I got here.
I've been knocking on
all the doors and nobody answered.
Until you did, so...
Thank you.
Birds.
The scariest thing was, uh...
when these people broke in, they...
they weren't wearing blindfolds.
It's like they didn't need them.
But they'd been outside.
You have to wear blindfolds.
Not these people.
These crazy guys
weren't affected like everyone else.
They wanted to see.
They were happy.
They were so glad.
And they said everyone needed to see.
Wait.
Get up and get out.
It's not an orphanage.
New guy, you had a great visit.
We really loved meeting you. Now fuck off.
And anybody who doesn't agree,
you go with him.
- Out now!
- Douglas, that is murder.
No. This is murder.
- Please.
- Letting strangers into this house.
Every contact we have had
with the outside has brought us death.
Lydia, Greg, Charlie.
If you wanna save people out there,
then you go right through that door
and you go do it.
We're not bringing
any more strangers in here.
Not while I'm alive.
I won't tell you again, get up and get...
Thank you.
You'll sleep in the garage.
The only reason I opened that door
is 'cause I remember
what it felt like to be outside of it.
If you guys hadn't let me in, I...
I feel like such a burden.
You are no more a burden than I am, okay?
- That's not true.
- It is. It is.
You're not soft like me.
I'm so spoiled.
My parents have always done
everything for me and then my husband,
and I just...
I got soft from all that love.
Well, I was raised by wolves,
so consider yourself lucky.
If something happens to me,
I want you to take care of my baby.
Okay?
- No. No.
- Please.
- It's your baby.
- Malorie.
No.
- Promise me.
- Nothing is gonna happen to you.
It's your baby.
- Promise me.
- Nothing...
Please promise me.
Yeah, okay. Yeah, of course.
What is this?
Well, if I was just gonna tell you,
I wouldn't have bothered
putting it in this fancy... this fancy bag.
I got it on the supply run.
- It's so cute.
- Mm-hmm.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
I know it's not the baby shower
you've always dreamt of.
No, it's... It's perfect.
And you can give it to your little one
when she's old enough, okay?
Thank you.
You guys, the river's speeding up.
It's time for a meeting.
I need to talk to you about the rapids.
The rapids are
where the water gets very bumpy.
It's very loud. It's very dangerous,
and it's gonna be
the hardest thing we have ever done.
And when we reach them, one of you
is gonna have a very important job.
One of you is gonna have to look.
And the person who looks,
they have to tell me
which direction to steer into
so that I go the right way.
Because if I look, we won't make it.
What if we see something?
- I'll do it.
- No, no, no, no.
I'm... I'm the one
who will say who looks, okay? I say it.
I'll say who goes. I'll say who looks.
I say who looks.
Testing. Testing. Hello?
Hello? Is anyone out there?
Hello? Testing, one, two, three. Hello?
Testing.
- I love this song.
- Me too.
- I've never actually heard it before.
- Hmm.
- It could be a false alarm, right?
- All right.
We're going upstairs to the bedroom.
We need towels, sponges,
um... scissors, and lots of water.
Buckets of water. It's okay. It's okay.
It's okay.
Take it easy. I've got you.
It's okay. It's okay.
Ah, the scissors are in the, um, drawer
by the side of your left hand. Yeah.
- Okay, so the baby's coming.
- No, not happening.
- Not happening.
- It's definitely coming.
- Come with me. Come with me.
- This is not happening.
It's happening. Let's go. Come on. Hey.
- I have to do the water.
- We'll do the water.
Okay, here we go.
- You two are doing great.
- Oh, shut up.
One more time.
Come on. Come on.
It's okay. It's okay.
It's a boy.
Oh.
No.
And your auntie thought you'd be a girl.
Hey, new guy. New guy, let me in.
Just come and unlock the door. Come on.
Let me out. What are you doing?
What?
What are you doing?
Gary?
Gary!
Hey.
Tom! He put the birds in the freezer.
Tom, I told you he's fucking crazy.
Ga...
Tom. Get the shotgun.
He's crazy.
What the fuck are you doing?
We let you into this house. We let...
No! No! Fuck.
Fucking asshole.
I knew you were a fucking lunatic.
You fucking piece of shit. We saved you.
Fuck!
- Almost there.
- That's right. That's right.
Yes! Yes!
Yes.
Oh.
You did it, Mama. You did it.
Hello.
You look so beautiful.
What's going on down there?
Can I see?
So beautiful.
Thank you.
Can I see yours?
Wow.
Hum.
Thank you.
Look at this.
- Olympia, cover your eyes.
- Isn't it beautiful?
No. Why are you doing this?
Gary, please don't do this.
- Look.
- Gary, please don't do this.
- Show the baby.
- No, no, no, Olympia.
Olympia, cover the baby's eyes.
Olympia.
See?
- Show your baby.
- Olympia, let me see your baby.
- You're not so bad.
Keep the baby's eyes covered.
Let me see your baby, just for one minute.
Olympia, let me hold your baby
just for one minute!
Just one minute.
Let me hold her for one minute, okay?
- One minute.
- See.
- Okay?
See!
No. Oh, no. Oh, please, no. Oh!
- See it. See it.
- No, no, no. No, no, no.
Hey, Malorie.
Give me the children.
Give me the kids.
Give me the children or I'll take them!
Hey, asshole.
Hey.
What are you doing here?
Have you come to see?
Open your eyes.
Don't be frightened.
Look at me. Look at me.
Look at me. Look at me!
Ow.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry that you didn't get to see.
It is beautiful.
So beautiful.
I'm sorry.
It shall cleanse the world.
Please don't. Please don't hurt us.
Please stay away from us.
Please. Please. Please. Please.
Please don't do this. Don't do this.
Please don't do this.
It's okay. It's okay. It's okay.
Listen to the clicks.
Listen to the sounds,
if they're softer or louder.
Listen to this.
Listen.
If they're louder,
you're in an open space. Do you hear that?
But if they're softer,
something is very close.
Please. Anyone. Hello? Hello?
Hello, hel...
Hello?
Check it out. Yeah.
There is nothing here.
- Let's go to another spot.
- Fucking time.
- Hey.
What's wrong?
I heard some of them again.
What?
A few of 'em...
driving around.
Driving around like
they're not blindfolded.
Okay.
No more runs alone.
What's this?
I was thinking like
a warning system for the kids.
- If they're in trouble, ring the bell.
- Right. That's nice.
How about this?
Oh, it's...
It's purely survival.
- Purely survival?
- Yeah.
Hello?
Is anyone there? Hello?
Testing. Testing.
If there is anyone there, please respond.
- Hello?
- Hello.
Who is this?
My name is Rick.
Rick, this is Tom.
We have a place.
A compound with enough supplies...
We have a community.
It's safe here.
We're down by the river's end.
- Where are you?
- Don't answer that.
Near Pike's Quarry.
Jesus. You're a ways away.
How many of you are there?
- Four of us.
- Hmm-mm.
Are any of them children?
- Don't, do not say anything.
- It's okay. It's okay.
No. Why?
Because the fastest way
to get here is by the river,
and I don't think
you could make it with kids.
Wait, the river?
Float downstream as far as you can.
Stay on the water
until you hit the rapids.
The water is fast there. It's dangerous.
We've lost some people.
You need to see clearly.
- What does that mean?
- What do you mean, see clearly?
You will have to look.
- I'm telling you.
- Rick, we'll have blindfolds on.
We can't look.
I'm glad you said that.
Someone will have to take a...
Prepare for two days' journey
at the pace of the river's current.
Bring supplies for longer.
How do I find you after the rapids, Rick?
You'll hear the birds.
We've got a lot of them.
Just follow the sound to us.
Down a small embankment,
you'll find a wall with a gate.
That's our...
- That's their what?
- That's our what?
Rick?
It could be real.
- No.
- Could be the truth.
- Could be is not good enough.
- What if Rick could help us?
And what if Rick is one of them?
Huh?
Wait, he knew about the birds.
Oh, my God. Gary knew about the birds
and he put them in the freezer.
I cannot believe
you're actually thinking about this.
Every house has run out of food.
We have to move.
You really don't think I know that?
You don't think I know that?
When I was little,
we had a boat just like this.
And every single summer,
we would take it to the lake.
Every summer.
You guys would have loved it up there.
They had trees. They had flowers.
The water was warm,
the clouds were in the sky.
We'd all play in the water.
All the kids, all the children.
We would all just run
up and down the shore.
There were other children in the world?
Yeah, just like you. Just like you.
Like you.
One day, we saw
this really, really big oak tree.
It was bigger than this house.
It was so big and old,
I couldn't see the top of it.
- Guess what we did?
- Climbed it.
We climbed it. Yes, we climbed it.
We climbed it and climbed it
until we got to the top.
Guess what we saw when we got to the top?
Boy! Girl! Time for bed.
But Tom's telling a story.
- Mal, let me just... We're almost done.
- I'm not gonna say it again. Come on.
Girl, come on.
Right now.
Come on.
Bed!
- What are you doing?
Now they think they're gonna go outside
and climb trees with all these new kids
- and see butterflies and flowers!
- It's a story.
It's not a story. It's a lie.
Because they'll never climb trees,
they are never gonna make new friends.
- Why make them believe that?
- They have to believe in something.
What is this for
if they don't have anything to believe in?
- So that they survive!
- Surviving is not living.
They're gonna die if they listen to you!
Life is more than just what is. It's
what could be. What you could make it.
You need to promise them dreams
that may never come true.
You need to love them knowing
that you may lose them at any second.
They deserve dreams. They deserve love.
They deserve hope. They deserve a mother.
They deserve a mother.
You haven't given them names, Mal.
Their names are Boy and Girl!
Think about that.
Every single decision I have made
has been for them.
Every single one.
You know what I saw?
At the top of the tree?
I saw a nest.
With five birds.
Sitting on the top branch.
And then they just flew away.
Got it. Got it. Sit. Sit!
It's safe. Come in.
Wow.
No, you did not.
- They're probably stale.
- Yeah.
Come here.
Just how I like 'em.
I'm sorry.
- Sorry.
- Me too.
Come here.
Kids.
This is strawberry.
This is what strawberry tastes like.
- What's that?
- Quiet.
Shh.
Anybody home?
Take the kids out the back.
I'll distract them.
If I'm not home in 15 minutes,
you take the kids to the boat and you go.
- I'm not leaving you!
- Mal.
- No, I'm not leaving you.
- Listen to me.
I love you so much.
I love you. Go.
- No!
- Go. Please go.
Be good. Go.
Go!
I'm coming out!
- Hey there, friend.
- Can I help you?
I don't think so, friend.
We can help you though.
No. Go!
- Take off your blindfold.
- Stand back.
- Stand back!
- She's not moving.
Hey. Got a woman and two kids over here.
They're coming.
They won't hurt you.
Fuck it. Fuck it.
On the contrary...
it's a beautiful thing, friend.
Listen to me.
I'm only gonna say this once.
We are going on the trip now.
It's going to be rough.
You have to do every single thing I say
or we will not make it.
Understand?
Where's Tom?
He's not coming.
It's time. It's time. It's time.
You remember the rapids?
Remember I told you about the rapids?
Well, they're close.
It is very dangerous and there's only
one way for me to navigate through them.
Somebody has to look.
- I'll look.
- No. I will decide! Okay? I will decide.
Just give me... Just give me a second.
I'll do it.
I love you so much.
Nobody's looking.
Okay, nobody's looking.
Okay?
Do your eyes. Let's do eyes.
Come on. Get on your knees.
Stay down low. Hold on tight.
Don't move. Hold tight.
Hold tight. Don't let go.
We're gonna be okay.
Hold on!
Please hold on. Hold on!
Ah!
Girl! Boy!
Girl! Boy! Boy?
Girl!
Malorie.
Boy!
- Keep calling me!
- Help!
- Malorie.
- Keep calling me.
Malorie!
- I'm right here.
- Malorie!
- I'm coming. Where are you?
- Malorie.
Where's Girl? Girl? Girl?
Keep ringing. I hear you. Keep ringing.
Keep ringing, Girl.
Keep ringing. Keep ringing.
Good girl.
Okay. Good job. Get up. Stand up.
Oh, good. Good, good, good.
Good girl. Okay.
Do you guys hear those birds?
That's where we're headed.
We just follow that sound.
Stay behind me.
Psst.
Dumb-dumb. Hey, dumb-dumb.
Open your eyes, Malorie.
Dummy. I'm right here.
No, no, no, no, no.
No, you're not.
No, no, no. No, no, no.
Malorie, look at me.
Look at me. Malorie, look at me.
- Malorie, look at me.
- It's not real. It's not real.
It's not real. It's not real.
it's not real.
- Malorie?
Malorie?
Malorie. Malorie.
Look at me, Malorie.
- Boy. Girl.
- Malorie.
Don't move. Stay right where you are!
Open your eyes.
Malorie, open your eyes.
Boy. Girl. Where are you?
Come with me. Look at me.
I need you. Just look at me.
Can I really take off my blindfold?
- Boy!
- It's safe?
No, that's not me.
No, no, no. Keep your blindfold on.
Boy, that's not real.
Keep your blindfold on. Listen to me.
Listen to my voice! This is my voice!
Girl, come with me. Look at me.
Take the blindfold off.
You can look at me.
Isn't it dangerous if I look?
No. No, I'm right here. I'm right here!
Do not take off your blindfold!
Please listen to me!
- Malorie.
- What? No.
- Please open your eyes.
- No. Girl, call out to me.
- It's just beautiful.
- Call out to me, please. Where are you?
Boy. Girl. Where are you?
Don't take my children.
Do not take my children!
Oh, baby, keep ringing. Keep ringing.
Keep ringing, baby.
I'm coming. Keep ringing.
Come on, keep ringing. Keep ringing.
Oh, my God. I've got you.
I've got you. We're good. Where's Girl?
Where's Girl? Where's Girl?
Girl. Girl! Girl!
Where's Girl?
She's scared of you.
What?
It's okay.
Uh...
Oh, I'm so sorry.
I'm so sorry, sweet girl. I'm so sorry.
I was wrong.
I shouldn't have been so harsh.
I shouldn't have stopped you from playing.
I shouldn't have ended Tom's story
because it wasn't finished.
When he climbed to the very top
of that giant oak tree,
he saw the most beautiful things.
He saw hundreds of children playing games.
Hundreds.
And he saw birds...
all different colored birds,
and... and he saw us.
He saw us from the very top.
He saw us together,
and we have to be together.
And it's not just a story.
It's not, because I have
so much I want to show you.
I have so much I want you to see. Okay?
But we have to do it together, okay?
So I just need you
to come to me right now, okay? Please?
Just come to me.
Baby, come to me, okay?
Oh! Ah.
I love you so much.
I love you so much. I love you so much.
We need to find the birds, okay?
Find the birds.
I want you to listen for the birds, okay?
Listen for the birds.
Okay, listen for the birds.
Just listen for the birds.
Malorie.
Be quiet. Quiet. Quiet. Quiet.
Malorie,
I know you're scared, but it's me.
Please. Where are you, Mal? I need help!
Just take a peek and find me.
Come on.
Go to the birds. Where are the birds?
Where are the birds?
The birds. Where are the birds?
That way.
I can't hear the birds!
It's too loud. It's too noisy!
Malorie! It's too loud!
This way!
Step. Step.
Hello! Hello! Hello!
Open the door. Please open the door!
My name is Malorie.
I'm Malorie. I have children.
Please find Rick and tell Rick we followed
the river and we followed the birds.
Malorie!
- Help!
- Look at me, Malorie!
- Please!
Malorie.
Okay. Just take the children.
Just take the children.
Take the children. They're just children.
Please let my children in!
- Please! Open the door!
- Look at me!
Let me see your eyes!
Okay.
She's okay.
She's okay. They're all okay.
Get Rick.
It's okay.
Malorie?
Yes.
I'm Rick. Come with me.
Okay.
Right this way.
You're inside and you're safe.
You can take your blindfolds off.
Come with me.
The birds.
They warn the sighted people
whenever those things are around.
It's not much, but it's something.
I'm going to get you some dry clothes.
Hey.
What do you guys say we let the birds go
and be with their friends?
Shall we do that?
Okay.
Malorie?
Malorie Hayes?
Dr. Lapham.
And what are your names?
Girl.
Boy.
Actually...
your name is Olympia.
Yeah.
Named after the sweetest girl I ever met.
And your name...
Your name is Tom.
Tom.
And I am their mother.
Would you like to
play with the other kids?
You want to go play?
Thank you. Thank you very much.